Aimee-Lewis 09@verizon.net, 610 304-5798

Education:

Widener University MA, and Certification in Special Education K-12 (ACHIEVED

August, 31 2013) (Graduation December 2013) with honors

Widener University BA, Psychology Graduated with High Honors

Member of CEC Council for Exceptional Children

Immaculata University 15 credit towards a Masters in Counseling Psychology

Objective:

To secure a position in a school public or private with school aged children Special Education Teacher, Consultant

Summary of qualifications:

Excellent Autism background, including: applied behavior analysis, discrete trial, verbal behavior, augmentative forms of communication (picture exchange system, sign language and AAC devices), using picture schedules and token systems, positive reinforcement and prompt strategies. I am experienced in implementing skill acquisition and behavior reduction programs individually and in groups, compliance training, creating social stories, knowledgeable about food allergies and special diets. Teach skills for functional use in life. I have a son who has autism; I use these skills professionally and personally.

Related Work Experience:

Special Education Teacher <u>Grades K-2</u> Chester Community Charter School, Upland, Pa (November 20014 to current)

- ★ Modified curriculum (<u>Journey's, GOMATH!</u>, and <u>Origo</u>) for the specific children's needs in all subjects
- * Responsible for creating lesson plans, modifying homework, projects and creating small group centers for children at all levels
- **★** Collaboration with regular education teachers and parents
- * Responsible for parent contact logs, anecdotal notes, data collection and progress monitoring
- **★** Created and interpreted data sheets on a daily bases
- ★ Create Individualized Education Programs (initials, revisions and annuals), create goals and special designed instruction to assist students in creating their academic goals
- * Created RTI intervention plans based on data folders created from three different data points
- **★** Used and created positive reinforcement and token systems based on a FBA

- **★** Encouraged and reinforced positive peer interaction and classroom management
- **★** Able to work within a co-teaching model, push in and pull out
- **★** Able to cover classrooms and teach whole group and small group lessons
- ★ Coordinate IEP meetings as case manager I make sure related services have their goals and present levels updated and schedule meetings
- **★** I have coordinated fundraising to raise money for technology in my classroom.
- ★ I teach the <u>writing summer program</u> and third grade <u>after school program called Back to</u>
 Basics.

Instructional coordinator Devereux cares, Downingtown, Pa (August 2002 to June 2003)

- ★ Use applied behavior analysis and Discrete Trial all day to provide support and gain success in mastering Individual Educational Program Goals
- * Responsible for lesson plans for circle time, writing activities, homework, medication logs and administering medication and snack that the children can prepare independently
- * Assisted in data collection, recording, and interpreting for individual education program goals
- **★** Created and interpreted data sheets on a daily bases
- **★** Used reinforcer assessment sheets and functional behavior sheets and created functional behavioral reports
- **★** Carried out sensory diets for sensory defensive children

1:1 special education assistant to a child with Autism, Aston Elementary School, Aston, Pa (November 2001 to August 2002)

- * Redirected undesirable behaviors with desirable behaviors
- **★** Modified curriculum for the specific child's learning needs
- **★** Encouraged and facilitated peer socialization
- **★** Communicated by using picture schedules, picture exchange communication system, social stories and sign language
- **★** Used positive reinforcements and token systems

Special Instructor, <u>Theraplay</u>, <u>INC</u>, Springfield, PA (July 2005 to 2007)

Special Instructor, Therapy alternatives, PC, Media, PA (January 2006 to Sept 2009)

Special Instructor, T.E.E.M.S, Aston, PA (May 2008 to may 2009)

ABA/VB Therapist, Educational Alternatives, Limerick, PA (Aug 2009 to Dec 2009)

Special Instructor, Sunshine Therapy Club, Drexel Hill, PA (November 2008 to October 2010)

Special Instructor, Kids and Family, INC, NJ (April 2010 to present)

Special Instructor, <u>Brighter Days</u>, <u>INC</u>, Pa (January 2011 to present)

- **★** Develop goals and objectives to fit the families' needs
- **★** Develop coping strategies for families
- **★** Assist families with community resources
- **★** Communication by using sign language, picture exchange system, AAC devices and verbal communication
- **★** Developing lessons and activities to help strengthen the needs of the child
- **★** Working with other disciplines to maximize resources and share information to ensure the child is getting best practices and well educated
- **★** Carrying out sensory plans and diets
- ★ Implement many autism intervention: Floor time (DIR), applied behavior analysis (ABA), verbal behavior programs, picture exchange systems (PSC), sign language and AAC devices for communication, function behavior assessments (FBA), behavior protocols
- **★** Created ABA programs based on needs
- **★** Collaboration and consultant skills

Related Skills:

Sign Language

Augmentative Communication devices and programs

PCS

Some Spanish

Computer aptitude: BoardMaker Plus, FlashPro, Excel, Powerpoint, Word, E-mail, IEP writer